Special Collection's Comic Book Collection 1934-1969
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Special Collection's Comic Book Collection 1934-1969 (bulk 1940-1950)
MS 474
Special Collecion's Comic Book Collection
The collection is comprised of comic books, from 1934-1969 (bulk 1940-1950) which are held in Special Collections.
6.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series
Series I: Comic books, 1934-1969
Scope and Content Note
A comic book is a magazine made of pictorial elements that tell a story. The narrative proceeds through the use of individual panels that represent different scene. Communication between characters is usually represented with “speech” or “word” balloons; as well as descriptive prose presented in text boxes. The comic books in this collection are indicative of many of the comics from this era. Printed on newsprint, and not properly cared for before introduction into this facility, many comics from this era are in quite poor condition. This collection is comprised of adventure, humorous, horror, cowboy, romance, war, science-fiction, and super-hero comics.
Access Terms
Kirby, Jack
Lee, Stan, 1922-
Comic books, strips, etc.--Periodicals
Abbott and Costello (Comic book)
America, Captain (Fictitious character)
Batman (Fictitious character)
Fantastic Four (Fictitious characters)
Flash (Fictitious character)
Superman (Fictitious character)
Tarzan (Fictitious character)
Tracy, Dick (Fictitious character)
Container List
- Series I: Comic books,1934-1969 (bulk 1940-1950)
  This series is arranged alphabetical, by title. Titles are taken from the cover and not from the copyright information from inside the comic. The title supplied does not include serial (series) title changes either.
  - Abbot and Costello Comics, vol.1 no. 1 and 4, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aces High, vol. 1 no. 1-4, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Action Comics, no. 90, 92, 93, 95, 98-103, 105, 107, 108, 111, 113, 114, 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adventure, vol. 88 no. 3, vol. 90 no. 1, vol. no. 5, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adventure Comics, no. 101, 102, 105, 110, 111, 114, 116, 118, 119, 122-144, 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Airboy Comics, vol. 2 no. 12, vol. 3 no. 4-6 and 9-12, vol. 4 no. 1-12, vol. 5 no. 1 and 2, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Al Capp’s Li’l Abner, no. 77, 82, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - All-American Comics, 69-88, 90, 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - All-American Comics, no. 91-95, 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - All-Flash, no. 20-26, 28-31, 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - All Star Comics, vol. 1 no. 1-12, vol. 2 13-24, vol. 3 25, 37, 40, 42,43, 1940-1948 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - All-Story, vol. 37 no. 1, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Amazing Adventure, no. 1 and 2, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Animal Comics, no. 17, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Apache Massacre, circa 1951 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Astonishing Tales of Science Fiction, vol. 1 no. 4, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bambi, no. 12 and 186, 1941-1948 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Barker, no. 1, 3-7, 9, 1946-1948 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Batman, no. 8, 26, 32, 34, 38, 39, 44, 45, 1942-1948 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Billy Boyd Western, vol. 1 no. 1, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bill Elliot Comics, no. 278, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Black Cat Comics, vol. 1 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Black Hood, vol. 1 no. 16, 18, 19, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Blondie in Eaten Out of House and Home!, no. 47, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Boy Commandos, no. 13-25, 1945-1948 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Boy Explorers, vol. 1 no. 1, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Buck Jones and the Iron Horse Trail, no. 299, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Captain America, vol. 1 no. 110, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - The Captain and the Kids, vol. 5 no. 8, 11, 56, 59 and two that are unnumbered, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Captain Marvel Adventures, circa 1946 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Captain Marvel Junior, vol. 13 no. 75, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Carl Anderson’s Henry, no. 1-3, 122, 155, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Charlie McCarthy and the Twenty Thieves, no. 171, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Classic Comics, no. 5-34, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Classics Illustrated, no. 35, 40, 46, 47, 51, 55-60, 62, 64, 67, 79, 80, 84, 91, 96, 98, 103, 105, 106 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Cody of the Pony Express, no. 34, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Comics on Parade Li’l Abner, vol. 5 no. 54, 58, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Conan the Barbarian, vol. 1 no. 3, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Copper Canyon, circa 1950 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Cow Puncher, no. 1-3, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Crime and Punishment, vol. 1 no. 38, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Crime Suspense Stories, vol.1 no. 25, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Curly Kayoe, vol. 1 no. 1, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dale Evans Comics, no. 1 and 2, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Detective Comics, no. 96-98, 101-105, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Dick Tracy, 133, 163, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Dick Tracy and Yogee Yamma, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Dick Tracy Comics Monthly, vol. 1 no. 1-23, 25-31, 33-38, 1948-1951 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Doctor Strange, vol. 1-5, no. 170, 1968, 1974 1968 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - The Durango Kid, vol. 1 no. 4, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Ella Cinders, vol. 1 no. 1, 4 1947 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Extra, vol. 1 no. 1 and 2, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Fantastic Four, vol. 1 no. 45 and 46, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Fast Fiction, no. 3 and 5, 1945-1950 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Fate, vol. 1 no. 3, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Fawcett Movie Comic, vol. 2 no. 10, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Feature Film Magazine, no. 3, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Felix the Cat, vol. 1 no. 1-3, 77, 119, 162, 1938-1948 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Fight Comics, no. 33, 38, 40, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Flash Comics, vol. 2 no. 23, vol. 6 no. 61, 63, 66, 68-70, 73-78, 82-85, 87-94, 1941-1948 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Flash Gordon, no. 173, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Flash Gordon Comics, vol. 1 no. 3, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Forever People, no. 3, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Gabby Hayes Western, vol. 1 no. 1, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Gasoline Alley, no. 1 and 2, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Gene Autry Comics, vol. 1 no. 2-5, 7, 9-21, 26 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Giant Comics Editions Gift Comics with Captain Marvel, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Girl’s Love, no. 11, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Great Detective, vol. 1 no. 1, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - The Gumps, vol. 1 no. 1-5, no. 73, 1936-1947 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Hap Hooper, vol. 1 no. 2, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The Haunt of Fear, vol. 1 no. 24, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Holiday Comics, no. 1, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hoot Gibson, no. 5 and 6, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Hopalong Cassidy, vol. 1 no. 2, 3, 5, 6, vol. 2 7-12, vol. 3 no 13-18, vol.4 no. 19-24, vol. 5 no. 25, 1946-1948 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Humphrey, vol. 1 no. 1, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Ibis the Invincible, no. 11, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Impact, vol. 1 no. 1, 4, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Jack Armstrong, no. 1-9, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Jim Hardy Comics, vol. 1 no. 2, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Jimmy Durante Comics, no. 18, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Joe Palooka, no. 1, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Joe Palooka Comics, vol.2 no. 3, 30, 1946-1949 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - John Wayne Adventure Comics, no. 1, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Jumbo Comics, no. 47, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Jungle Comics, no. 42, 43, 45, 47, 48, 50, 53-56, 58-61, 65, 68, 70-75, 77-88, 90, 94, 96-98, 1943-1948 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - The Katzenjammer Kids, no. 1, 3, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Kerry Drake, no. 3-5, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Kerry Drake Detective Cases, vol. 1 no. 6-13, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Kid Eternity, no. 1-10, 1946-1948 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Lash LaRue Western, vol. 1 no. 6, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Li’l Abner Comics, vol. 2 no. 61-68, 1947-1949 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Little Iodine, vol. 1 no. 2, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Little Orphan Annie, no. 1-3, 52, 152, 1938-1948 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - The Lone Ranger, no. 1-6, 27, 118, 125, 136, 151, 1946-1950 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Mad Hatter, vol. 1 no. 2, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Mandrake the Magician, no. 52, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Mansion of Evil, no. 129, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Marge’s Little Lulu, no. 4, 74, 110, 115, 131, 158, 165, 1945-1947 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Mister Miracle, no. 2, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Montana, circa 1950 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Monte Hall starring in Pioneer Marshal, circa 1950 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Monte Hale Western, vol. 5 no. 29 and 30, vol. 6 no. 31, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Movie Comics, vol. 1 no 2-4, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Movie Thrillers with Burt Lancaster in “Rope of Sand,” no. 1, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Mutt and Jeff, vol. 2 no. 19, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Nancy and Fritzi Ritz, vol. 5 no. 5, vol. 6 no. 9, 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - New Gods, no. 1, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - New York World’s Fair Comics, circa 1940 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - The Old Witch’s Grimm Fairy Tale, (Missing Cover), undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Ozark Ike, no. 180, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Panic, vol. 1 no. 2, 6-11, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Panther Jet, (Missing Cover), undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Piracy, vol. 1 no. 1-7, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Pogo the Possum, no. 1-3, 6-16, 1949-1954 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Popeye and Wimpy, no. 70, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Popular Comics presents Tiny Tim, vol. 1 no. 144, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Popular Love, vol. 16, no. 2, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Popular Sport, vol. 12 no.1, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - The Pride of the Yankees: The Story of Lou Gehrig, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Psychoanalysis, vol. 1 no. 1, 3, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Ranger Comics, no. 49, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Real Western Hero, vol. 12, 70 and 71, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Red Ryder Comics, no. 40, 43, 44, 47-50, 1946-1947 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Rip Kirby, no. 51, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Robin Moderne (in French), undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Rocky Lane Western, vol. 2 no. 9, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Rod Cameron Western, vol. 1 no. 1, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Roy Rogers Comics, no. 124, 144, 153, 160, 166, 167, 1946-1947 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Roy Rogers Comics, vol. 1, 1-11, 16, 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Sad Sack Comics, vol. 1 no. 1-3, 5, 6, 1949-1950 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - The Saint Comics, no. 1-3, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Santa Claus Funnies, no. 91, 175, 1945-1947 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Sheena, no. 11, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Shock Suspense Stories, vol. 1 no. 12, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - The Shoplifter’s Shoe, no. 50, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - The Silent Towns, (Missing Cover), undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Singing Guns, circa 1950 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Skyman, no. 3, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Smilin’ Jack, no. 1-3, 80, 149, 1940-1948 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Super Comics, vol. 1 no. 116, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Sparkle Plenty, no. 215, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Sparkle Watts, no. 6 and 7, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Star Spangled Comics, no. 45, 49-78, 1945-1948 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Star Spangled War Stories, no. 145, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Steve Canyon Comics, vol. 1 no. 1-5, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Strange Adventures, no. 1, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Strange Tales, vol. 1 no. 167, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Stuntman, vol. 1 no. 1 and 2, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Sub-Mariner, vol. 1 no. 27, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Superman, no. 27, 35-38, 40-42, 44-47, 51, 233, 1944-1971 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Sur la Planete Rouge, (in French), undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Tales from the Crypt, vol. 1 no. 24 and 42, 1951-1954 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Tarzan, no. 1-4, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Tarzan and the Fires of Tohr, no. 161, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Terry and the Pirates, vol. 1 no. 3-14, 1947-1949 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Tillie the Toiler, no. 150, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Tim Holt, no. 14, 17, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Tim McCoy, vol. 1 no. 16, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Tom Mix Western, vol. 1 no. 1-6, vol. 2 no. 7-12, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Les Tribulation de Bricole, (in French), undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Two Gun Kid, vol. 1 no. 3, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - The Vault of Horror, no. 36 and 37, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Walt Disney’s…, no. 79, 92, 116, 141, 157, 819, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Watchmem, no. 4 of 12, 1986 undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Western Comics, no. 1, 2, 4, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Western Fighters, vol. 1 no. 2, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Where Creatures Roam, vol. 1 no. 1, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Whiz Comics, circa 1946 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Wild West, vol. 1 no. 1 and 2, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Winnie Winkle, no. 1, 2, 174, 1939-1948 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Witches Tales, vol. 1 no. 3, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - The Witching Hour, no. 14, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Zane Grey’s, vol. 1 no. 27-29, 31, 34-39, 270, 357, 372, 433, 449, 467, 484, 511, 532, 583, 604, 616, 632, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 21)